<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on hit jim dot com</title>
    <link>http://hitjim.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on hit jim dot com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 23:33:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://hitjim.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta First Post - Setting Up a Personal Site with Hugo and Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://hitjim.com/2015/11/21/yawwwn-meta-first-post-setting-up-hugo-on-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 23:33:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hitjim.com/2015/11/21/yawwwn-meta-first-post-setting-up-hugo-on-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d done it a half dozen times before.  Scorch the earth on my webserver, start a new database and spin a new Wordpress blog with the purest of intentions.  But this time would be different!  It always is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-time-is-different-i-m-going-to-use-ghost:a93f96bc828519b95e3919f91015fb5a&#34;&gt;THIS TIME &lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt; DIFFERENT!  I&amp;rsquo;M GOING TO USE GHOST!!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Ghost a few times on teams and it&amp;rsquo;s really nice.  Not throwing stones here.  But I had that nagging feeling as I dug into guides for setting up Ghost on Digital Ocean.  I fretted over which Linux distro to use, or whether to allow comments.  Tangents and rabbit holes abound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-don-t-need-that:a93f96bc828519b95e3919f91015fb5a&#34;&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; that.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need simplicity.  I need speed.  I need ease or near-absence of maintenance.  I need to type words and have them display on a screen.  I need a static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d heard great things about Jekyll, and if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t recently been learning Go, maybe I would finally be playing with Ruby.  But today is not that day.  So &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d noticed a few peers were hosting their blogs and portfolio sites on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.  Awesome, source control plus free webhosting.  Now I don&amp;rsquo;t have to shell out money each year to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; update my blog.  Wait&amp;hellip; I mean, &lt;em&gt;this time will be different!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I quite easily found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; for using Hugo to publish static websites on Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;words-are-for-reading:a93f96bc828519b95e3919f91015fb5a&#34;&gt;Words are for reading.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I will continue adding content to this site in the same way you see here.  I may ramble at bit at times.  But I will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; just share my victories and paint them as flawless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasted a good evening trying to follow the steps at the top of the guide linked above, which was intended to establish a &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch for a project repo.  That was NOT what I wanted.  It&amp;rsquo;s no big surpise that I got build errors when I tried to have a &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch in a repo named such that it gets automatically built as a github page.  I scrolled further into the guide to find the steps accurately and obviously titled &amp;ldquo;Host Personal/Organizational Pages.&amp;rdquo;  After swearing at myself and some pro-level face-palming, I continued on my quest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-s-the-gist:a93f96bc828519b95e3919f91015fb5a&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the gist.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/install&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/installing/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Github repo for building site and authoring content - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hitjim/hitjim-hugo&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hitjim/hitjim-hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Github repo for hosting site.  You can witness the litany of errors in the early commit history! - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hitjim/hitjim.github.io&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hitjim/hitjim.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locally clone and enter &lt;code&gt;hitjim-hugo&lt;/code&gt; repo, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x#installation&#34;&gt;install a theme I liked&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then ape the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zyro/andreimihu.com/blob/master/config.toml&#34;&gt;config file from the author of that theme&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; for my own config file at the root dir of the project, while making the appropriate personalizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;hugo server --watch -t hyde-x&lt;/code&gt; to start a local dev server that watches and updates when it detects changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;hugo new about.md&lt;/code&gt; to make and then edit my about page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;hugo new post\meta-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt; to to make and then edit this very post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder as instructed and run &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; on its own for the final build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy contents of &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;hitjim.github.io&lt;/code&gt; repo, create a CNAME file containing my only my domain name &lt;code&gt;hitjim.com&lt;/code&gt;, and push changes to Github.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure my domain registrar to play nicely with Github Pages.  Much of &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/my-custom-domain-isn-t-working/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; helped me get it right.  In my case, I just needed &amp;ldquo;A Record&amp;rdquo; type entries, one with host &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; and another with &lt;code&gt;www&lt;/code&gt;, and each one pointing a static IP for Github Pages - &lt;code&gt;192.30.252.153&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;192.30.252.154&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be possibly a little too pleased with myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>